ADITI SHARMA

https://github.com/aditisharma0612 • 9354563195 • aditisharma061203@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/aditi-sharma-4a39b827b

SUMMARY

A tech enthusiast with a passion for coding and building problem solving skills using DSA and data analysis. My journey in the world of technology has been fueled by a diverse array of interests, ranging from front-end web development with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, to database management systems like MySQL and data analytics tools like Python and R with good knowledge of Tableau ,Power BI . Currently I'm learning ML ,AI ,DL, NLP based concepts for my upskilling in the field of Data Science. I'm excited to connect with fellow enthusiasts, collaborate on projects, and continue my journey of exploration and learning in the ever-evolving landscape of technology.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Science Intern, MS Interface Techonolgy Pvt .Ltd

May 2024 - Present

- Implemented data cleaning, data modelling, data visualization technique to various projects assigned to me during internship.
- Technical Skills: Power BI, Tableau, DL, ML, Python, Java.

Data Analytics Intern, YBI Foundation

March 2024 - April 2024

- Implemented data cleaning, data modelling, data visualization technique to various projects assigned to me during internship.
- Learned and implemented data analytics techniques including python,R,matplot,etc.

Web Development and Designing Intern, Oasis Infobyte

Jan 2024-Feb 2024

• Collaborated with mentors to work on creating landing page of cafe .

PROJECTS

Fitnesstrack (Data analytics tracking of activities on fitness watch)

- Fitnesstrack is use to track your daily BP,BMI,walking, respiration,calories burn analysis .
- Uses Data Analytics tools to track the record using graphs,data manipulation and data visualization technique.
- Associated with Microsoft Code Without Barrier Hackathon.

House Price Prediction System

 Used HTML,CSS, JAVASCRIPT to create a house price prediction model so that one can buy,sell ,rent accordingly.

Travel Website (Al chatbot)

- Travel website which provide weather forecast and perfect plan for trip duration. Also provide relevant hotels, restaurants, and flight/train transportation.
- Associated with AMERICAN EXPRESS MAKEATHON.

Unemployment Analysis

• Analysis of unemployment rate based on their level of education and employment rate.

Movie Recommendation System

Built ML and Statistical Model for movie recommendation.

EDUCATION

Dronacharya College of Engineering, Gurgaon

2022-Present

B.Tech Computer Science and Engineering with current CGPA of 8.2/10

Dev Samaj Vidya Niketan Sr.Sec.School,Gurgaon Senior Secondary 2022

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- **Technical Skills:** Java ,C++, Advance DSA, Python, R , C, HTML,CSS, JS, matplotlib ,Bootstrap, NumPy, Pandas, MySql, Data Structure and Algorithm.
- **Participation:** Flipkart Runway Round 1, Microsoft Code Without Barrier Hackathon, American Express Makeathon, MLSA Cloud Challenge, GSSoC '24, Myntra HackerRamp.
- Certifications: Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate, Data Structure, UC, San Diego
- Awards/Activities: Data Analytics and Visualization Job Simulation by Accenture sponsored by Forage, Graphic Design Lead at Google Developer Students Club-DCE.